# Rishabh Agarwal

E-mail: rishabhaga@gmail.com § Phone: +91-9741374980

# CAREER OBJECTIVE

To learn Software and Computer Skills, and contribute to the developments in the field of Computer Science and Information Technology by involving in continuous learning and research and to achieve career progression and personal development by working as a Software Developer in an Organisation.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Flipkart Internet Pvt. Ltd

Jan 2015 — Present

Software Development Engineer II

Currently working as a part of 3PL (3rd Party Logistics) Team, where we are working towards streamlining and create easy process for vendors on-boarding.

## Flipkart Internet Pvt. Ltd

July 2013 — Dec 2014

Software Development Engineer I

I was working as a backend engineer for the mobile website team as well as web-views for retail apps. Worked on major launches in Flipkart which includes PREXO (product exchange), Large Appliances, NDD (Next Day Delivery), SDD (Same Day Delivery), Flipkart First Subscription Service, Mi (Xiaomi) Store.

Integrated Flipkart new, highly scalable checkout service from scratch for both mobile-site and retails apps. Developed many in-house services which made a deep impact on business like User-Agent parser service which helps Flipkart to run channel-based offer, fraud detection and many others.

# Flipkart Internet Pvt. Ltd

Jan 2013 — Jun 2013

Engineering Intern

Worked in the mobile website team and developed the perceived performance analysis tool, in which the user perceived data was captured using JS(raw data), queries was run on it using Hadoop and Hive and output (knowledge) was properly displayed on dashboard which helped mobile website for performance tracking.

#### SKILLS

Programming Languages: PHP(Expert), Java (Intermediate), Ruby (Beginner), Fluent in C/C++

Database: MySQL

Programming Environment: Vim, IntelliJ, RubyMine

Scripting Language: BASH, Python

Web related knowledge: HTML, Javascript Platforms Used: Mac OSX, Linux, Windows

# **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Technology (Honors)

Jul 2009 — Jun 2013

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Allahabad

Rishabh Agarwal

Grade: 8.66

ISC - Class 12th 2008 — 2009

St. Paul's College, Lucknow

Grade: 88.50%

ICSE - Class 10th 2006 — 2007

St. Paul's School, Lucknow

Grade: 89.30%

# **INTERESTS**

Competing in programming competition Reading Technical Blogs ,Technical News and Startups Blogs Watching Documentary

# PERSONAL DETAILS

Current Location – Bangalore Date of Birth – 30th September, 1991 Skype – rishabhaga

Rishabh Agarwal 2